Curriculum vitae

PERSONAL INFORMATION Antoine Wehenkel



36 Avenue Blonden, 4000 Liège (Belgium)

+32497069146

antoine.wehenkel@uliege.be

Date of birth 28 Sep 1995 | Nationality Belgian

PERSONAL STATEMENT

"We know the past but cannot control it. We control the future but cannot know it." Claude Shannon

In 2018, I was graduated in computer engineering (Msc) from ULiège. I spent my last year of study at Ecole Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL) as an exchange student. There, I did my master's thesis in the laboratory of Professor Jean-Yves Le Boudec, which was about the parameters estimation of electrical distribution networks' lines. I am now a PhD student (FNRS Research Fellowship) in machine learning at ULiège (Belgium) under the supervision of Professor Gilles Louppe. The subject of my thesis lays at the intersection between likelihood free inference and deep learning.

My main research interests revolve around Statistics, Machine Learning and Information Theory.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Oct 2018-Present PhD candidate in Machine Learning

ULiège, Liège (Belgium)

Deep Learning for Intractable Inverse Problems in Science

The primary goal of this research project is to develop deep learning algorithms for solving intractable inverse problems, as ordinarily found in a broad class of scientific disciplines.

Sep 2016–Jun 2018 Master in engineering, Intelligent systems

ULiège, Liège (Belgium) Summa Cum Laude

Sep 2017–Jun 2018 Exchange student in the master of data science

EPFL. Lausanne (Switzerland)

Average score: 5.8/6

Sep 2013–Jun 2016

Bachelor in engineering (major in computer science, minor in electrical engineering)

ULiège, Liège (Belgium) Magna Cum Laude

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jul 2017-Sep 2017 Student Worker

Laboratory of Immunology, ULiège

Curriculum vitae Antoine Wehenkel

Development of an RFID based tracking system for fish. It required to chose the right hardware components, to program micro controller (Arduino), to create a web server (Django and PostgreSQL) and a monitoring system (Python).

Student Researcher Jul 2016-Apr 2017

Smart grids laboratory, ULiège

Work in the smart grids research lab, in collaboration with Engie. The purpose of my work was to develop optimisation algorithms applied to electric vehicle fleet integration in the electrical network.

Sep 2016-Dec 2017 Student instructor

EPFL & ULiège

Student instructor for the following courses:

- Electronic 2 (Prof. Kayal EPFL)
- Data Structures and Algorithms (Prof. Geurts ULiège)
- Analysis and Design of Electrical Measuring Systems (Prof. Vanderbemden ULiège)
- Computer Organisation (Prof. Boigelot ULiège)

PUBLICATIONS & AWARDS

Publications

- Unconstrained Monotonic Neural Networks, A. Wehenkel, G. Louppe Submitted to Neural Information Processing Systems 2019
- Parameter Estimation or Three Phase Untransposed Short Transmission Lines from Synchrophasor Measurements, A. Wehenkel, A. Mukhopadhyay, J.-Y. Leboudec, M. Paolone -Submitted to IEEE Transactions on Instrumentation and Measurement
- Recurrent machines for likelihood-free inference, A. Wehenkel, A. Pesah, G. Louppe MetaLearn Workshop @ Neurips 2018
- An App-based Algorithmic Approach for Harvesting Local and Renewable Energy Using Electric Vehicles, A. Dubois, A. Wehenkel, R. Fonteneau, F. Olivier, D. Ernst - ICAART 2017

Honours and awards

- FNRS Grant (Research Fellowship; 2018 2022)
- Best Master's thesis award from AIM (2018)
- Best Master's thesis award from AILg (2018)
- Physics award for outstanding student (2013)
- Physics award at belgian olympiades (2012 and 2013)

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue

French

Other languages

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
B2	C1	B2	B2	B2

Digital skills

English

- Excellent programming skills in Python, C, C++, Matlab, Java and Scheme.
- General expertise in Optimisation, Statistics, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Deep Learning, Data Mining.